我觉得不太舒服
I don't feel so good.
小可怜 怎么了
Aww, what's going on?
让我看看
Let's see.
你有点发烧啊
You are kinda warm.
或许应该把毯子掀开散散热
Maybe get rid of some of these blankets?
真可爱啊
Aw, that is cute.
你为了过万圣节打算吓我
You tried to scare me for Halloween.
这怎么可能没有吓到你呢
How in the world did that not frighten you?
其中有些还是我的真血呢
Some of this is my actual blood.
我在安装的时候把自己划伤了
I nicked myself putting it on!
亲爱的 你完全不知道要怎么吓人
Sweetie, you don't know the first thing about scaring people.
关键在于"可信度"
It's all about plausibility.
你刚刚也太淡定了
And you were awfully casual
完全不像一个胸口被斧头砍中的人
for a guy who just got an ax in the chest.
如果你真的想吓我
You know, if you really wanted to scare me,
你应该等到我打开衣柜门时
you should've waited until I opened the closet
发现你用一条领带上吊死了
and found you hanging by a necktie.
什么烂主意
Excuse me!
我自杀吗
I killed myself?!
是啊 这很有可信度
Yeah. Totally plausible.
你傻乐了这么多年
I mean, you've been so happy all these years,
抑郁肯定会在某一天爆发 不是吗
the other shoe is bound to drop, right?
顺便说下
By the way,
我也不是很信用领带上吊这一套
I am not married to the whole necktie thing.
也可以是...
It could be, um...
举枪自尽或服毒自尽
shotgun or poison
或者用电钻钻眼睛...
or a power drill to the eye --
打住 打住
Stop. Stop!
现在你真的吓到我了
Now you're scaring me.
高手一出手 便知有没有
That's how you do it.
万圣节快乐啊
Hey, happy Halloween!
本来是快乐的 却被你妈毁掉了
It was until your mother ruined it.
他只是在生气
Oh, he's just mad
他试图吓我却失败了
because he tried to scare me and he couldn't.
我很难被吓到的
I'm tough to scare.
我女朋友怀孕了
My girlfriend's pregnant.
-不要 -菲尔
- No! - Phil.
她都跟我们差不多大了
She's our age.
如果她都怀上孕了 会上新闻的
If she was pregnant, it'd be on the news.
但这招不错
But good one.
爸 对不起
Dad, I'm sorry.
我今早又没时间帮你把这个送过去
I don't have time to drop this off for you again.
艾达·梅·曼恩
Ida Mae Mann?
这不是那个整日坐在窗前的孤独妇人吗
Isn't that that lonely little lady that sits up in her window?
他总是强迫我帮他送邻里协会的材料
He always makes me deliver his neighborhood association stuff
因为他害怕她
because he's afraid of her.
这也太离谱了
That's crazy!
我经常去那个房子的啊
I go by that house all the time.
这画面真不迷人 菲尔
Not hot, Phil.
好吧 她很瘆人
Fine! She's creepy!
她像商店的招财猫一样整天坐在窗前
She sits in that window like a store cat.
好吧
Okay.
我会在跟比尔去吃晚餐时顺带送过去的
I'll drop it off on the way to dinner with Bill.
他要带我去好食餐厅 预约的6点
He's taking me to Buon Cibo's at 6:00.
我也要跟珍妮丝去好食餐厅 也是6点
I'm going to Buon Cibo's at 6:00 with Janice.
好恶心 我可不想看着你
Ew! I don't want to watch you
对她使用烂俗的泡妞手段
run your discount body-spray game on her.
把你的预约时间改到晚一点
Change your reservation to later.
臣弟做不到
I can't.
她必须在睡前4小时用餐
She has to eat four hours before bed
否则就会出现胃反酸
because of the reflux.
-你改时间吧 -不行
- You change. - No!
我们吃完要去看《德州电锯杀人狂 》
We're going out after to see "Texas Chainsaw Massacre,"
我也不敢相信我竟然同意去看了
which I can't believe I agreed to.
那听上去好有趣啊 我从没看过这电影
Ooh, that sounds like fun. I've never seen that movie.
你敢信吗 我这个"克大胆"竟然没看过
Can you believe that? Me, of all people.
那我们必须去看了
Uh, then we're going.
你觉得已经没有任何东西能吓到你了吗
You think you can't be scared anymore?
那是我看过的最吓人的电影了
That's the most terrifying movie I've ever seen.
好极了 放马过来吧
Great, bring it.
我很期待被吓到
I look forward to being scared.
我竟然怀孕了
I'm pregnant?
菲尔
Phil!
你买到装扮服了吗
Did you get the costumes?
是的 我时间不够
Yeah, I -- I didn't have a lot of time,
于是我从上班的地方偷了些东西来
so I had to steal something from work.
求你不要...
Please don't...
评判[法官袍]
judge.
好吧 这个开头还算过得去
Okay, that's not a bad start.
我觉得我可以用这个发挥一下
I think I can work with this, yes.
莉莉 上别针
Lily, my pins!
万圣节让我们激动万分
We are so excited for Halloween.
多年来第一次
You know, for the first time in years,
我们打算潇洒走一回
we're gonna get a little cray
去参加盛大的同志万圣节嘉年华
and go to the big gay Halloween carnival,
就像我们当初青春年少 膝下无子时那样
like we used to when we were young and childless --
那年"潇洒走一回"这说法也还没过时
And people still said "Cray."
以前我们总是把莉莉拴在身边
We -- We've always had Lily with us in the past,
但我们现在正在努力培养她的独立性
but we are on a crusade to make her more independent,
所以当有人邀请她参加一个派对时 我们就...
so when she got an invite to a party, we sort of, uh --
-立刻替她回复会参加 -是的
- RSVP'd for her. - Yeah.
但说实话 让她出去
But you know what? It's gonna be good for
跟她同年纪的人社交一下对她有好处
her to socialize with people her age,
而我们出去跟年纪只有我们一半的人社交也有好处
and good for us to socialize with people half our age.
好啦
Okay.
米奇
Mitchell...
朱迪法官[著名电视人物]
Judge... Judy.
你的才能
Your talent...
你简直像被基佬天使亲吻过一样
It's like you were touched by a gay-ngel.
你之前还说我们再也不会穿
And you said we would never wear
参加胡娇婚礼时穿过的伴郎鞋了呢
the groomsmen shoes from Pepper's wedding again.
稍等一下 小姑娘
Just a second, young lady.
我们很高兴你今晚要去参加派对
W-We're very happy you're going to this party tonight,
你不觉得这个装扮服 性暗示意味太明显吗
but, uh, isn't this costume a little, uh, suggestive?
这就是我在拉拉队的真队服
This is my actual cheerleading outfit.
你们知道我参加拉拉队了吧
You guys know I'm doing that, right?
是啊 是啊 当然啦 肯定知道啦
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah. Totally.
我们应该知道这事的 对吧
We should have known that, right?
乔 你提前回来了吗
Oh, Joe, you're home early?
我准备了一个惊喜...
I got a surprise for --
曼尼
Oh. Manny.
我知道你吃母乳吃到能走路的年纪
Look, I know you breastfed until you could stand,
但你现在还玩不给糖就捣蛋 年纪大了点吧
but aren't you a little old to be trick-or-treating?
这不是为万圣节准备的
This isn't for Halloween.
我的单人秀正处于最后的排练阶段
I'm in final rehearsals for my one-man show
《西格蒙德·弗洛伊德:自我再出发》
"Sigmund Freud: Here Ego Again."
我给你留了四张票 但如果你需要更多...
I've saved you four seats, but if you need more --
不用 四张够了
No, four's good.
话说 到底是什么惊喜
So, what's the surprise?
是给乔的啦
Well, it's kind of a Joe thing.
他正跟他朋友一起在外面讨糖吃
You know, he's out trick-or-treating with his friends.
我等他回来再给他看
I-I'll wait till he comes home to show it to him.
偏心地对待你的儿子们
Hmm, playing favorites with your sons,
可能会无形中重复
perhaps unconsciously repeating the cycle
你父亲造成的...
your own father perpetuated on --
一张票就够了
You know, one ticket's gonna be good enough.
屋里真的冷 还是因为我扮成
Is it cold in here, or is it just me
《冰雪奇缘》里的冻人美女所以觉得冷
because I am the frozen lady from "Frozen"?
你为什么还不穿你的装扮服
Why aren't you wearing your costume?
"随它吧" 歌洛莉亚 随它吧
Let it go, Gloria. Let it go.
但是你说过既然乔跟德文一家出去了
But you said that since Joe was out with Devon's family
我们就要一起找点乐子
that we were going to do something fun together.
对 找乐子 喝杯威士忌
Yes, fun. Have a Scotch,
给斯黛拉穿那件变异蜘蛛装扮服
put that mutant spider costume on Stella --
好吧 我自己去找米奇跟小卡
Fine, I'll go meet Mitch and Cam by myself.
但等乔看到我给他的大惊喜时
But you're gonna miss Joe's reaction
你就看不到他的反应了
when I give him my big surprise!
一个糖果棒而已啊
It's just a candy bar!
一年半前 在一个未曝光事件中
18 months ago, in an underreported news event,
娜迦零食食品公司
NagaSnacki Food Solutions
停产了有史以来最棒的糖果棒
discontinued the greatest candy bar of all time.
老软糖
The Fudgy Duddy.
经过艰难的搜索
After an exhaustive search --
就谷歌了一下
One Googling.
我找到了这个尤物
...I tracked down this beauty.
现在我儿子可以体验到我们从小吃到大的
Now my son can experience the kind of quality confection
高品质糖果了
our generation grew up with.
什么我们
"Our"?
我是X一代的 可不是你们婴儿潮时代的
I am a Gen X. Don't make me a Boomer.
上周发生了一件很可怕的事情
Something horrible happened to me last weekend.
我要...
I'll just have the...
海鲜沙拉
seafood salad.
好的 您的丈夫呢
Very good. And for your husband?
不不 他是我丈夫
Oh, no, no. He's my husband.
他说的就是丈夫
That's what he said.
我一直害怕的一天终于来了
The day I have dreaded finally came --
人们开始直接判断我是杰的...
people assume that I am Jay's...
老婆
wife.
孩子们玩得开心
You kids have fun!
曼尼 你在干什么
Manny. What are you doing?
防止你的房子被扔鸡蛋啊
Saving your house from being egged.
你的糖果都送完了
You're all out of treats.
还好我找到了一个糖果棒送出去
Luckily I found a candy bar to give away.
糟糕
Oh, no.
我的老软糖没了
My Fudgy Duddy's gone!
不许动
Nobody move!
你好 两张《德州电锯杀人狂》的票
Hello there. Uh, two for "Texas Chainsaw Massacre."
抱歉 几周前就卖完了
Sorry, that sold out weeks ago.
要在我们的网站上更新啊 伯纳德
Which should've been updated on our website, Bernard!
不过有一部超吓人的
But we still have seats
日本电影还有票
for that super scary Japanese film.
-可以 -稍等
- Yes! - Uh, pause.
有多吓人 有多日本
How scary? How Japanese?
返老婴儿杀人案
"Make Dead with Old-Face Baby."
-请给我们两张票 -不
- Two, please. - No, um...
拜托 亲爱的 你答应我要看恐怖电影的
Come on, honey, you promised me a good scare.
肯定好看啦
This'll be fun!
-好吧 -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
不
No!
你怎么样
How you doing?
很好 我好害怕
Great. I'm so scared.
别糊弄我
Don't patronize me.
你以为我看不出来你是装的吗
You don't think I can tell when you're faking it?
"菲尔 好棒好爽啊"
"Oh, Phil, mmm. It's so good."
我知道你讨厌我的秋葵浓汤
I know you hated my gumbo.
打扰一下
Uh, excuse me.
我在里面有些煎熬
Uh, I'm having a hard time in there.
我本来是来看一部我已经看过的电影
I -- I came to see a movie I'd already seen.
我知道所有突然吓人的地方
Knew where all the jump scares were.
你能告诉我这电影里哪些地方最吓人吗
Could you tell me where the big ones are for this one?
抱歉 哥们儿 我还没看过
Sorry, dude. Haven't seen it.
我看过
I have.
天啊
Ohhhh! God.
还好
It's okay.
他在门后
He's behind the door.
他在门
He's behind the --
你有问题吧
Something is wrong with you!
这里都变了
Wow. This place has changed.
这里以前更...
It used to be so much...
基一点
gayer.
直男直女们老是抢走我们最好的东西
Straight people always take our best stuff.
一开始 他们抢我们的早午餐 我没说什么
First, they came for our brunches, and I said nothing.
嘿 诺姆 丹妮斯
Oh, hey -- hey, Norm! Hey, Denise!
嘿 姑娘们
Hey, girlfriends!
我们...不能那样说吧
I...don't think we can say that.
确实不能
You can't. Yeah.
等等 莉莉不是在你们家开派对吗
Wait. I-I-Isn't Lily at a party at your house?
-对啊 -你们不是要在场监护吗
- Yeah. - That you're chaperoning?
本来是的 可是后来来了一帮大孩子
That was the plan, but then a bunch of older kids showed up,
所以我们觉得不会有什么事
so we figured they'd be fine.
再见 碧池们
Bye, bitches!
这可以说 我是女的
It's okay. I'm a girl.
好吧 大孩子 没有成年人
Okay, older kids, no adults.
好吧 我们现在是几级恐慌
Okay, where are we on the panic scale?
你们在这儿
There you are.
谢谢你们救了我
Thank you for saving me from a night
省得听杰说一晚上他的老软糖
of listening to Jay talk about his Fudgy Buddy.
抱歉 我们刚发现莉莉在一个无人监护的派对中
Sorry. We just found out Lily is at an unsupervised party.
你们要我查一下她的照片分享网吗
Oh, you want me to check her Insta?
莉莉 她还有上这社交媒体吗
Lily -- Lily has Insta?
你有这个的账号啊
You have Insta?
怎么 你觉得我老到不能用不了这网站了吗
What, you think I'm too old to have Insta?
好吧 我想听你到底经历了什么
Okay, I-I want to hear all about what you're going through,
但要先找到
right after we figure out --
-我找到她了 -好吧
- I found her! - Okay.
-看样子她玩得很开心啊 -好吧
- And looks like she's having fun. - Okay.
她旁边那个帅哥是谁
Who is this cute boy next to her?
你能转一下屏
Can you turn it ar--
那是加斯 我一直就不信任他
Okay, that's Garth. I -- I've never trusted him.
我看他九岁的时候就在买体香剂
I saw him buying deodorant when he was 9.
那是啤酒吗
Is that a beer?
-我 -别站在那里
- Okay, I'm... - Don't just stand there!
-我要给她打电话 -打电话
- I'm going to call her! - Call her!
我没想到今晚这么冷
I didn't think it was gonna be so cold tonight.
很抱歉 我可能有点不在状态
I'm sorry if I seem off.
只是最近
It's just that lately,
人们常误以为我是年纪更大的...
people have been mistaking me for a much older --
女士 请问你是迷路了吗
Excuse me, ma'am. Are you lost?
我找不到我的朋友了
I can't find my friends.
我帮你找
Let me help you.
真是个好心的年轻人
Oh, what a nice young man.
放开我啦
Get off me!
或许这根糖果棒代表着你失去的童真
Perhaps this candy bar represents your lost innocence?
它就代表美味的巧克力而已
It represents delicious chocolate.
你确定你是把它给了一个蜘蛛侠吗
You're sure you gave this to a Spider-Man?
我确定
I'm sure.
而且很难不注意到
You know, it's also hard to ignore
你找的这个物品形状像阴茎
that this object you seek has a phallic shape --
我当年为毛劝你放弃念哑剧专业
Why did I talk you out of that mime major?
蜘蛛仔 十一点钟方向
Spidey -- 11:00.
蜘蛛侠 等等
Spider-Man! Hold up!
老子才不是蜘蛛侠 是死侍好吗
I'm not Spider-Man, okay? I'm Deadpool.
是两个截然不同的角色
It's a totally different character.
听着 在我还没意识到
Look, before I realized
那糖果棒是这男人必死命运的象征时
it was a symbol of this man's mortality,
我不小心给了你
I accidentally gave you some candy bar --
不是普通的糖果棒 是老软糖
Not "some" candy bar, a Fudgy Duddy.
听着 我来告诉告诉你们
Look, you kids should know about this.
七零年代时 曾有一个风靡全美的广告
There was a famous commercial back in the '70s,
头一次有女生在电视上碰触篮球
first time on TV a girl touched a baseball.
包装纸是红蓝相间的 上面还有...
It's got a red and blue wrapper with a --
对 我想起来了
Oh, yeah, I remember.
看起来很恶心 我就给我妈了
It looked gross, so I gave it to my mom.
她刚出门去西好莱坞参加那个嘉年华了
She just left to go to that festival in West Hollywood.
形容一下她
Describe her.
她有点害羞 很喜欢动物
She's kind of shy, loves animals --
不是 是她的装扮服
No, her costume.
她扮成家政女王玛莎·斯图尔特
Oh. She's dressed as Martha Stewart.
很讽刺 因为我晚餐是吃麦片打发的
Ironic, since I had cereal for dinner.
跟我来 我需要你
Come with me. I need you.
在精神上支持你吗
For emotional support?
走拼车道需要人
Carpool lane!
希望这句话听起来不会太多愁善感 但...
I hope this doesn't sound too mushy, but...
我真的很喜欢和你乱搞
I really love hooking up with you.
我不愿去想
Well, I hate to think
我害你没去参加万圣节狂欢
I'm pulling you away from some Halloween fun.
就是跟你那些更...年轻的朋友开派对
You know, partying with your more...youthful friends.
说什么傻话 珍妮丝
Hush, silly Janice.
如果我对年轻的东西感兴趣
If I was interested in youthful things,
我现在又怎么会跟你坐在这里
would I be here with you?
宝贝 你都不知道我有多想你
Aww, babe. You have no idea how much I've missed you.
我还是多少知道一点的
I think I have some idea.
比尔离开了几周 去扑灭山火
Bill's been away fighting a forest fire for weeks.
他打了一次电话给我 说他想念我
He called me once to say he missed me,
于是我给他发了一张我穿着可爱衣服的照片
so I sent him a pic of me in a cute outfit.
我预期他会发句惊叹或惹火的表情
I expected "Wow" or a fire emoji.
然而我收到的是
Instead I got...
"再发点露奶照"
"Send more boobs"?
我没生气 但我不想把这变成日常
I'm not mad, but I don't want to make it a habit
就是发...裸照
of sending...nudes.
等等 你真的发了露奶照吗
Wait. You actually sent boob pics?
是啊 你到底吸入了多少浓烟
Yeah. How much smoke did you inhale?
这不是我的电话号码 艾丽克斯
This isn't my number, Alex.
你就是用这号码打给我的啊
It's the one you called from.
因为我的手机没电了
Because my phone died.
我就借用了怪咖克雷格的手机
So I borrowed Creepy Craig's.
等等
Wait.
你发了一张裸照给怪咖克雷格吗
You sent Creepy Craig a naked photo?
艾丽克斯
Alex!
老天鹅啊 你发了11张
Oh, my God! There's, like, 11?!
你...
Well, you --
是他一直问我要嘛
he kept asking!
你以为我跟怪咖克雷格一样变态吗
You think I'm as pervy as Creepy Craig?
我又不认识怪咖克雷格
I don't know Creepy Craig!
但他对你的认识可"透彻"了
Well, he knows you!
你真觉得我会这样不尊重你吗
You really think I would disrespect you like that?
"我"还提过什么要求
What else did "I" ask for?
别看了
Oh, don't.
天啊 你这是在外面吗
Oh, my God. Are you outside?
我一直都担心
You know, I've always worried
我们可能太不相同
that maybe we were just too different,
但你居然认为我能写出这种下流话
but the fact that you think I'm capable of writing
"现在改用屁股 用杂志打屁股"
"Do butt now -- hit with magazine"?
其实我觉得
You know what?
我们不合适 艾丽克斯
This isn't working, Alex.
不 等等
No, wait!
你至少能不能叫克雷格删掉那些照片
Can you at least ask Craig to delete those?
我想你知道该怎么联系他
I think you know how to reach him!
相信我 我这辈子的万圣节恶作剧
Trust me, I've had enough Halloween mischief
已经玩够了
for one lifetime.
我准备好过这种生活了
I'm ready for this now.
你心智真成熟
You are such a mature person.
我都无法想象你狂野贪玩的样子
I can't even imagine you as a wild child.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
五年前 我们袭击了一栋房子
Five years ago, we hit this one house.
那家人每次都报警抓我们
The family was always calling the cops on us
因为我们丢点燃的烟花
for lighting off fireworks.
都是常见的那一套
Standard stuff --
用卷纸撒满他家 往汽车油箱里倒糖[会凝结]
TP, sugar in the gas tank --
然后 我注意到他们
but then I noticed they had
有大约20个那种傻兮兮的花园地精摆设
like 20 of those stupid garden gnomes.
-天啊 -就是啊 什么老太婆品味
- Oh, my God. - I know, so douchey.
于是我们把地精摆成性交姿势 然后按门铃
So we posed them having sex, rang the doorbell,
等他们一开门 我们就把地精炸上天
and then when they opened the door, we blew them up.
你没懂好笑在哪里吗
Are you not getting it?
笑点是有点隐晦啦 就是...
It's kind of subtle, so --
那是我家
That was my house.
但你住在公寓啊
But...you live in a condo.
现在是的
Now.
几年前 我公公去世了
Years ago, my husband's father died
留下了一套古董地精公仔收藏
and left us his antique gnome collection.
马蒂想把地精放在屋子里
Marty wanted to keep them in the house.
他说它们能让他平静下来
They soothed him, he said.
因为外面响个不停的烟花
'Cause the constant fireworks
总是引发他的创伤后遗症
were always triggering his PTSD.
所以我坚持叫他把他唯一的遗产放在屋外
So, I insisted he put his sole inheritance outside,
结果就被你炸飞了
where you blew them up.
生活有它独特的幽默感
Life's funny.
是啊
Yeah.
第二天
Yeah, the next day,
我本来要去婚姻咨询处和他会合
I was supposed to meet him at couples therapy.
但我没赶上 因为我的车坏了
But I didn't make it 'cause my car died.
油箱里有糖
Sugar in the tank.
所以我错过了那次咨询
So I missed the appointment.
他去买咖啡
He went for a coffee,
爱上了咖啡师
fell in love with the barista,
现在我住在公寓楼
and now I am living in a condo,
和小屁孩约会
dating a friggin' child!
珍妮丝
Janice.
现在提这个或许不是时候 不过
This may be a bad time to mention it, but...
我的钱不够付泊车费
I don't have enough money for the valet.
莉莉还是不接电话 你追踪她的定位了吗
Lily is still not answering. Did you track her location?
是的 上面说她回家了
Uh, yeah. It says that she's at our house?
你觉得她把那男孩带回家了吗
Do you think she took that boy home?
当然带回家了
Of course she did!
家里没人 那么多安妮塔·贝克的唱片
An empty house, all those Anita Baker records.
那是镇上最性感的地方
It's the sexiest place in town.
我们必须回家
We have to get home!
想从这人潮中挤出去得花上一小时
Okay, it's gonna take us an hour just to get out of here.
不 我们只要从这个迷宫走
No, no, we can save ourselves 20 minutes
就能省二十分钟
just by cutting through this maze.
不 我讨厌这些玩意
No! No. I-I hate those things.
米奇尔 我们基本算是逼自己女儿
Mitchell, we basically forced our daughter
对发情的青少年投怀送抱
into the arms of a hormonal teen.
说实话
And let's be honest,
我们到底是想让她更独立一些
was it because we wanted more independence for her
还是自己
or for us?
那好
All right.
拿出点气魄来
Now, try to have some backbone.
我就在这 知道吗
I'm-I'm-I'm right here. Okay?
记住 这都是为了我们女儿
And just remember, this is for our daughter.
小卡
Ohh, Cam...
我知道这让我听起来很肤浅
I know it makes me seem shallow,
但他的身材赞爆了
but he had such a crazy body!
我怎么再去面对那些宅男的身材
How am I supposed to go back to nerd butts?
无论我需要什么 她包里都有
No matter what I'd need, it'd be right there in her purse --
创可贴 湿巾 葡萄干
Band-Aids, wet wipes, raisins.
因为有时我不是真的生气
Because sometimes I'm not angry.
只是饿了
I'm just hungry.
你知道她包里没有什么吗
You know what she's not gonna find in that purse?
比你更好的人
Someone better than you.
-真的吗 -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
你能找到比她更好的
You can do better than --
我一时想不起她名字 反正是茉莉的老妈
I'm forgetting her name right now, so Molly's mom.
要知道 我不是因为你安慰我才安慰你
You know, I'm not just saying it because you said it,
但我一直都觉得比尔配不上你
but I never thought Bill was good enough for you.
真的吗
Seriously?
你值得拥有聪明又有求知欲的人
You deserve someone smart and curious.
说实话 他每次出门时都说
Be honest, didn't you get sick of him saying
"我赌我能从那上面跳过去" 你没听够吗
"I bet I can jump over that" every time he walked outside?
谢了 卢克
Thanks, Luke.
我们不需要他们 对吗
We don't need them, right?
再过几周
In a couple weeks,
我们会把他俩都忘干净
we won't remember either one of them.
消防员
A fireman?
修女
A nun?
珍妮丝的口味特别重
Janice was into some really weird stuff.
是她吗 那是玛莎·斯图尔特吗
What about her? Is that a Martha Stewart?
我觉得那是戴妃
I-I think that's Princess Di.
杰 你得做好心理准备
Jay, you have to prepare yourself.
我们的糖果棒可能找不回来了
We may not find your candy bar.
我们已经问过四个玛莎·斯图尔特
We've stopped four Martha Stewarts,
两个赏金猎人老狗和朱迪斯·赖特本人
two Dog the Bounty Hunters, and the real Judith Light.
顺带一提 她人真好
How nice was she, by the way?
是啊 落落大方 接着找
Yeah, class act. Keep looking.
是老妈
Hey, that's Mom!
-妈 -曼尼
- Mom! - Manny!
我跟你说过多少次 扮成老头的时候
How many times have I told you not to shout "Mom"
不要大声叫我"妈"
when you're dressed like an old man?
算上这次 就这一次
Including now? Once.
对不起 我不是生你的气
I'm sorry. I'm not mad at you.
我是气米奇和小卡把我丢在这
I'm mad at Mitch and Cam for leaving me here
那个刻薄的童子军又让我觉得自己好老
and the mean Boy Scout that made me feel so old.
老
Old?!
亲爱的 你看起来娇艳极了
Sweetie, you look delicious!
-真的吗 -真的
- I do? - Yes.
你现在就过来跟我们跳舞
You're dancing with us right now.
好
Okay.
看我在地上发现了什么
Look what I found on the ground.
已经太迟了
We're too late.
抱歉 杰
Sorry, Jay.
你想谈谈此刻的感受吗
Do you want to talk about it?
不 我不想看起来像可怜虫一样
No! I don't want to seem like a sad sack.
不好意思
Excuse me.
这个糖有什么特别的
What is it about this candy?
有夏天的味道 我说不好
It just tasted like summer or something,
我不知道
I don't know.
但一代新糖换旧糖
But out with the old, in with the new.
糖果棒停产了
Candy bars come and go.
唱片店都不见了
No more record stores.
六岁的儿子长大了
6-year-old sons too grown up
万圣节不愿意跟老爸去要糖果
to go trick-or-treating with their dads.
没人再用传呼机了
No more beepers.
乔不想跟你过万圣节
Are you that bummed that
让你这么低落吗
Joe didn't want to spend Halloween with you?
不 那只是一个阶段的开始 你懂吗
No! It's just the beginning of the whole thing, ya know?
一旦撕开那个封条
When you-when you break that seal...
我知道乔今晚想和朋友们一起玩
Look, I know Joe wanted to be with his friends tonight,
但他肯定还会想跟老爸过万圣节的
but he'll definitely want to spend another Halloween with his dad.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
孩子们总会回头的
Kids have a way of coming back.
哪怕不得不为此编个可笑的借口
Even if they have to... make up a dumb reason to do it.
万圣节快乐 孩子
Happy Halloween, kid.
等等 这件事要谨慎处理
Wait, this is a delicate moment.
我们要是没处理好会吓到她的
We could scar her if we don't handle it right.
老天 我知道你这话没错
God, I know that's true.
我的初吻特别可怕
My first kiss was terrible.
我妈撞见我吻一个女孩
My mom walked in on me with this girl.
我至今仍能听到我妈对我爸大喊
I can still hear my mom scream to my dad,
"我就说他不是同性恋"
"I told you he wasn't!"
我的更糟
Well, mine was worse.
我没跟你比惨
It's not a competition.
我爸发现我在谷仓里
My dad found me in a barn
跟橄榄球训练假人舌吻
open-mouth kissing a tackling dummy.
你赢了
And you win.
好 我们要温柔但坚定
Okay, so, gentle, but firm.
-知道吗 -知道
- Okay? - Yeah.
亲爱的 你还好吗
Sweetie, is-is everything okay?
我没事 走开
It's nothing. Go away.
宝贝 是不是有男生
Honey, did-did a boy pressure you
逼你做你不想做的事了
to do something you didn't want to do?
恶心 才不是呢
Ew! Gross! No.
那是不是有女生逼你做你不想做....
D-Did a girl pressure you into doing something --
天啊 你能不能去领养另外一个孩子
Oh, my God! Can you adopt a second child
然后别这么目光都聚焦在我身上啊
to take some of this off of me?!
亲爱 亲爱的 我们只是想帮帮你
Honey -- Honey, we -- we just want to help, okay?
我们只是担心或许我们强迫了你
We're -- We're afraid that maybe we pushed you
去参加你还没准备好参加的派对
into going to that party before you were ready.
是这样的 我以为有个男生很喜欢我
Look, I thought this boy really liked me,
结果他只是利用我来接近我朋友凯利
but he was just using me to get to my friend Kelly.
-凯利吗 她很辣鸡啊 -对啊
- Kelly? Ew, she's gross! - Yeah.
她才没有呢 她是我的朋友
No, she isn't. She's my friend.
但她比不上你啊 任何选她而不选你的人...
She's not you. And anyone who would pick her over --
你当然会这么说啦 你是我的爸爸
Of course you'd say that. You're my dad.
抱歉 你们说什么都安慰不到我的啦
I'm sorry, there's nothing that you could say that would help.
懂了吗
Okay?
你们不是女生 你们也不是十二岁
You're not a girl, you're not 12.
你们怎么可能会懂那种
What would you know about liking a boy
喜欢一个男生而人家不喜欢你的感觉
who doesn't like you back?
亲爱的...
Oh, honey --
我去给大家拿点冰激凌
I'm gonna get us some ice cream.
好啦 你过来 你过来
Okay, come here, come here.
好啦
Okay.
老公 你不能因为
Honey, you can't be mad
我看那个电影不被吓到而生气啊
that I wasn't scared by that movie.
它就是个婴儿啊
It was a baby.
它有三排牙齿呢
It had three rows of teeth!
婴儿乳齿啊
Baby teeth!
这的确不是你的错啦
Look, it's not your fault.
只是在你旁边这么比较起来 我就像个孬种
It's just that, next to you, I feel like such a wuss.
只是因为你会因为一部电影
Just because you get a little
而有点发神经不代表你就是...
bit squirrelly in a movie doesn't make you --
等等 我们为什么要过马路
Wait, hang on. Why are we crossing the street?
我们家就在这条街底...
Our house is right down --
等等 你不会是
Wait a minute, you're not
害怕经过那个小老妇人的家吧
afraid of the little old lady's house, are you?
你怎么知道人家小不小
You don't know she's little!
我们对她唯一的了解就是她坐在那里
All we know is she sits up there
在窗前谋划着什么邪恶的计划
plotting evil from her window.
她不在那里了
She's not there.
她不是总是在那里吗
She's always there!
一切今天为止
This stops now.
我们现在就去敲人家门
We're gonna go knock on that door,
自我介绍一下
introduce ourselves,
然后让这件神经事就此了结
and put an end to this nuttiness.
开门时机有些诡异啊
Well, that's weird timing.
那个...
The, um...
艾丽克斯来递送的东西
The envelope Alex dropped off.
老太太都没有来收耶
The -- The old lady never picked it up.
什么声音啊
What was that?
天啊 菲尔 她摔倒了可怎么办
Oh, God. Phil, what if she fell?
我们进去看看她
We should go check on her.
大概吧
Yeah, I guess so.
我... 你先走我马上来
I am, uh, right behind you.
我去找一把手电筒
I'm just gonna go find a flashlight.
菲尔
Phil --
您好
Hello?
曼恩太太
Ms. Mann?
您好
Hello?
艾达·梅
Ida Mae?
曼恩太太
Ms. Mann?
简单扼要 一刀毙命
It was simplicity itself.
一年前 克莱尔第无数次说我
A year ago, Claire accused me for the millionth time
这辈子都吓不到她 所以我想出了一个计划
that I couldn't scare her, so I came up with a plan.
我就把房子买给一堆欧洲人夫妇
I'd just sold a house to a European couple
他们短期内都不会住到这房子里来
that weren't gonna take possession for a while,
然后呢 去年秋天"艾达·梅"就搬来了
so, uh, last fall, "Ida Mae" moved in.
我就跟你说吧
I told you!
她整天都坐在那楼上
She's always up there!
幸好这房子就在克莱尔的慢跑路线中
Fortunately, the house was right on Claire's jogging route,
所以很轻易就能介绍艾达·梅给克莱尔认识
so it was easy to introduce Claire to Ida Mae,
而当我想加大剂量时
and when I wanted to amp it up,
我让艾达·梅跟她打交道了
I had Ida Mae make contact.
时间到了今早
Then, this morning...
我知道斧子的把戏吓不到克莱尔
I knew that ax wouldn't scare Claire.
所以我故意用这招来引诱她
I just did that so she'd accuse me
再次说我这辈子都吓不到她
of not being able to scare her.
关键在于"可信度"
It's all about plausibility.
太他妈对了
Damn right, it is.
在过去这一年
Over the past year,
艾达·梅加入了邻里协会
Ida Mae joined the neighborhood association,
为她跑掉的狗贴过海报
hung up a poster for her lost dog,
签名申请过慈善送餐活动
signed up for Meals on Wheels.
其实还蛮好吃的呢
They're not bad, by the way.
她还打了很多毛线呢
Also, she got a lot of knitting done.
抱歉啊 克莱尔
Oh, I'm sorry, Claire.
我吓着你了吗
Did I scare you?
-这是你干的好事吗 -是啊
- You did this? - Yep.
你计划这件事多久了
How long have you planned this --
11个月2周又3天之前
11 months, two weeks, and three days ago,
我让艾达·梅·曼恩降临到这世界上
I gave birth to Ida Mae Mann.
因为我就是最强的人[与名字音似]
Because I da main man.
菲尔 不许现在玩谐音梗
Oh, don't you dare do word play, Phil.
抱歉
Sorry.
因为我真是开心死啦
I was having so much fun!
-什么 -我之前总是在想
- What? - I was wondering what we were gonna do
未来这30年 当我们的孩子们
for the next 30 years of our lives
都离我们而去时 我们人生有何盼头
without the kids in the house.
但现在我知道了
And now I know --
你也开始扭曲了 我喜欢死了
you're getting twisted, and I like it.
游戏开始
Game on.
"游戏开始" 你这"游戏开始"是什么意思
"Game on"? What do you mean "Game on"?
游戏 游戏已经结束了啊
It's -- It's game over.
没这回事
Nope.
万事小心啊 兄弟
Watch your back, buddy.
这游戏一定会非常非常有趣
This is gonna be so much fun.
我们不能就去旅行吗
Can't we just travel?
你妈去哪了
Where'd your mom go?
优胜者诞生啦
We have a winner!
我今天真的很需要这份鼓励
I really needed this today.
抱歉借过
Excuse me.
那是我老婆
Hey, that's my wife!
想得美啊 宝贝儿 癞蛤蟆也想吃天鹅肉
Sure! Sweet heart. Like you could get that.
不 不是的 他真是我老公
No, no, no. That is my husband.
她知道这是...
Does she know that...
不知道 我们也得一直守住这秘密
No, and we are never gonna tell her.